In 1962, Buckminster Fuller
في عام 1952، قام بكمينيستر فيولر
presented the particularly audacious proposal for the Geoscope.
بعرض فكرة جريئة للمنظار الجغرافي
It was a 200-foot diameter geodesic sphere
والذي كان عبارة عن كرة جغرافية بقطر 200 قدم
to be suspended over the East River in New York City, in full view of the United Nations.
بغرض أن تعلق فوق النهر الشرقي لمدينة نيويورك، أمام مبنى الأمم المتحدة
It was a big idea, for sure, and it was one that he felt could truly inform
كانت فكرة ضخمة، بالتأكيد، وقد كانت فكرة شعر فيولر بأنها تستطيع توفير المعلومات
and deeply affect the decision making of this body
وتأثر بعمق على عملية اتخاذ القرار في تلك المنظمة
through animations of global data, trends
وذلك عن طريق عرض بعض الصور المتحركة عن البيانات الدولية ، واتجاهات حركة هذه البيانات
and other information regarding the globe, on this sphere.
ومعلومات أخرى عن العالم ، على هذه الكرة
And today, 45 years later,
واليوم، بعد 45 عاما
we clearly have no less need for this kind of clarity and perspective,
نحن بكل وضوح لا نقل حاجة لمثل هذا الصفاء في التفكير والنظرة
but what we do have is improved technology.
ولكن لدينا تقنيات متقدمة
Today we don't need one million light bulbs to create a spherical display.
اليوم لا نحتاج مليون لمبة لصنع شاشة كروية
We can use LEDs.
يمكننا استخدام الصمامات الثنائية باعثة الإضاءة (الصمامات)
LEDs are smaller, they're cheaper, they're longer lasting, they're more efficient.
وذلك لأن الصمامات أصغر و أرخص و أعمارها أطول، وأكثر كفاءة
Most importantly for this, they're faster.
والأهم بالنسبة لهذا التطبيق أنها أسرع
And this speed, combined with today's high-performance micro-controllers,
وهذه السرعة، مصحوبة مع معالجات الحاسب السريعة المتوفرة اليوم
allows us to actually simulate, in this piece,
سمحت لنا بأن نحاكي، في هذه القطعة
over 17,000 LEDs -- using just 64.
التأثير المشاهد لأكثر من 17,000 صمام -- بإستخدام 64 صماما فقط
And the way this happens is through the phenomenon of persistence of vision.
والطريقة التي يحدث بها ذلك هو عن طريق ظاهرة استمرار الرؤية
But as this ring rotates at about 1,700 rpm -- that's 28 times per second.
في حين أن هذه الحلقة تدور 1,700 دورة في الدقيقة -- أي ما يعني 28 دورة في الثانية الواحدة
The equator's speed is actually about 60 miles per hour.
تكون سرعة المنطقة الوسطى واقعيا 60 ميلا في الساعة
There are four on-board micro-controllers
هناك أربع معالجات في الجهاز
that, each time this ring rotates
والتي، مع كل دورة لهذه الحلقة
it, as it passes the rear of the display,
تقوم، بينما تعبر في خلف الشاشة
it picks up a position signal.
تلتقط إشارة الموقع
And from that, the on-board micro-controllers
ومن هذه الإشارة ، تقوم المعالجات
can extrapolate the position of the ring at all points around the revolution
باستنتاج موقع الحلقة في جميع النقاط حول المحيط
and display arbitrary bitmap images and animations.
وتظهر صورا وتحركات
But this is really just the beginning.
ولكن هذا في الحقيقة مجرد البداية
In addition to higher resolution versions of this display,
إضافة الى نسخة ذات دقة أعلى من هذه الشاشة
my father and I are working on a new patent-pending design
أعمل أنا وأبي حاليا على تصميم
for a fully volumetric display using the same phenomenon.
شاشة حجمية كاملة باستخدام نفس الظاهرة
It achieves this by rotating LEDs about two axes.
وتحقق ذلك بتدوير بعض الصمامات حول محورين
So as you can see here, this is a, eleven-inch diameter circuit board.
فكما ترون هنا، هذه دائرة كهربائية بقطر 11 بوصة
These blocks represent LEDs.
هذه الأجزاء تمثل الصمامات
And so you could see that as this disc rotates about this axis,
بذلك يمكنكم رؤية أنه مع دوران القرص حول هذا المحور
it will create a disc of light that we can control.
ستنتج قرص من الضوء يمكننا التحكم به
That's nothing new: that's a propeller clock;
هذا ليس بجديد، حيث هذه فكرة الساعة المروحية
that's the rims that you can buy for your car.
هذه هي الجنوط التي يمكنكم شرائها لسياراتكم
But what is new is that, when we rotate this disc about this axis,
ولكن الجديد، هو أنك حين تدير القرص حول هذا المحور هنا
this disc of light actually becomes a sphere of light.
يتحول قرص الضوء إلى كرة من ضوء
And so we can control that with micro-controllers
ونستطيع التحكم بذلك عن طريق المعالجات
and create a fully volumetric, three-dimensional display with just 256 LEDs.
ونحصل على شاشة عرض حجمية ثلاثية الأبعاد بـ 256 صمام فقط
Now this piece is currently in process --
هذه القطعة لا تزال في طور العمل
due out in May -- but what we've done is we've put together a small demo,
ومتوقع أن تكون متاحة في شهر مايو، ولكن ما قمنا به هو أننا قمنا بتطويرعرض تجريبي مصغر للفكرة
just to show the geometric translation of points into a sphere.
فقط لإظهار تحول النقاط هندسيا الى كرة
I've got a little video to show you,
لدي فيديو صغير أعرضه
but keep in mind that this is with no electronic control,
ولكن تذكروا أن هذا بدون أي تحكم إليكتروني
and this is also with only four LEDs.
وهو أيضا بأربع صمامات فقط
This is actually only about 1.5 percent of what the final display will be in May.
مما يمثل في الواقع 1.5 % فقط من الشاشة النهائية في مايو
So, take a look.
خذوا نظرة
And here you can see it's rotating about the vertical axis only, creating circles.
وهنا يمكنكم رؤية الصمامات تدور حول المحور الرأسي فقط، لتحدث دوائر
And then, as the other axis kicks in,
والآن، بينما يتحرك المحور الآخر
those actually blur into a volume.
تتحول الرؤية الى منظر مجسم
And the shutter speed of the camera
علما بأن سرعة الغالق في الكاميرا
actually makes it slightly less effective in this case.
تجعلها أقل فعالية في هذه الحالة
But this piece is due out in May.
ولكن هذه القطعة ستجهز في مايو
It'll be on display at the Interactive Telecommunications Spring Show
ستعرض في معرض الاتصالات التفاعلية هذا الربيع
in Greenwich Village in New York City -- that's open to the public,
في قرية جرينتش في مدينة نيويورك -- وهو مفتوح للعامة
definitely invite you all to come and attend -- it's a fantastic show.
أدعوكم بكل تأكيد للحضور -- إنه معرض رائع
There are hundreds of student innovators with fantastic projects.
هناك مئات الطلاب المخترعين بمشاريع رائعة
This piece, actually, will be on display
أما القطعة الحالية ، ستكون معروضة الآن
down in the Sierra Simulcast Lounge
في بهو سييرا سملكاست
in the breaks between now and the end of the show.
في الاستراحة من الآن وإلى نهاية المؤتمر
So I'd love to talk to you all, and invite you
لذا أحب أن أتحدث معكم جميعا، وأدعوكم
to come down and take a closer look.
للقدوم وأخذ نظرة أقرب
It's an honor to be here. Thanks very much.
إنه لشرف أن أكون هنا، أشكركم جزيلا
(Applause)
(تصفيق)